## Vyron Vasileiadis

Software Engineer & Trainer

### Personal Info

E-mail

hi@fedonman.com

**WWW** 

https://fedonman.com

LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/fedonman

#### Skills

Web Development

Game Development

Machine & Deep Learning

Internet of Things

Remote Sensing

Microsoft Azure

**Training & Coaching** 

Problem Solving

Senior Software Engineer specialized in Web Technologies with a keen interest and experience in Microsoft Azure, Internet of Things, Smart Cities, Machine & Deep Learning, Ocean Remote Sensing and Quantum Computing.

Microsoft Certified Trainer adept at planning and implementing onsite and remote training programs. Authoritative and clear communicator with a charismatic style and insightful approach.

Based in Athens, Greece. Open to remote positions or attractive relocation packages.

#### **Work History**

#### 2016-10 -Current

#### **Technical Trainer**

PeopleCert, Athens, Greece

- Trainer at Alliance for Digital Employability Coding Bootcamp, a 14-week intensive training course, where previously unemployed candidates with no ICT background are re-skilled and certified by PeopleCert as full-stack developers
- Trained over 1000 hours and more than 300 students
  Python, C#, ASP.NET, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
  Angular, React, as well as generic software skills such
  as algorithms, design patterns, OOP, functional
  programming, testing, scrum
- Collaborated with leadership to assist in lesson plans, instructional materials and written practice tests

#### 2014-09 -2017-04

#### Co-Founder & Lead Developer

Open.tech, Athens, Greece

- Co-Founder of open.tech, a collaborative creative agency in Greece specialized in innovative technologies and the web
- Lead Developer on a plethora of projects for a variety of clients including luxury villas, apartments and hotels, top Greek fashion designers, theatrical groups and the Greek government
- Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs
- Managed a team of 5 developers and designers

2013-10 -2014-06 Web & Game Developer

Pegneon, Athens, Greece

- Implemented company's website, API and integrated solutions into business operations
- Designed and developed company's main product, an educational game about safety and hygiene in co-working spaces

2012-05 -2012-10

#### **Web Developer**

IT Development Spain, Granada, Spain

- Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in website projects
- Used various technologies to make code repairs and optimize corporate website

#### **Education**

2015-10 -2017-10

## Master of Science: Space Science, Technologies & Applications

University of Peloponnese & National Observatory of Athens - Greece

- The first and only Higher Education Programme in Greece in the domain of Space
- Thesis: "Advancements in monitoring the Mediterranean Sea with the use of Copernicus data"

2007-10 -2013-03

# Bachelor of Science: Computer Science & Technology

University of Peloponnese - Greece

- Thesis: "CoveX: Quantum Circuit Simulator"
- Elected as Student's Representative for 4 consecutive years

## **Certifications**

2019-01	Microsoft Certified Trainer
2019-01	Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate: Web Development
2019-06	Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Engineer Associate
2019-06	NVIDIA Deep Learning for Computer Vision

### **Additional Training**

- Copernicus Marine Service for the Aquaculture Sector, Athens, Greece, 24 - 25 September 2019
- ESA Advanced Ocean Remote Sensing Training
   Course at Porto, Portugal, 11 17 September 2017
- Third International Ocean Colour Science Meeting at Lisbon, Portugal, 15-18 May 2017
- Quantum Complex Systems Summer School at University of Vienna, Austria, 22 - 26 September 2014
- Workshop on Quantum Simulations at Universidad del Pais Vasco UPV/EHU, Bilbao, Spain, 22-25 October 2012

## Volunteering

- Technical Trainer at Social Hackers Academy is an NGO programming school for refugees & unemployed EU Nationals
- Mentor at innovation hackathons co-organized by Crowdpolicy and Greek public sector